准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
重生的蟹老板
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
开
关
打烊时间
Closing time
一天最快乐的时间
the happiest time of the day
打烊时间
Closing time
一天最悲伤的时间
the saddest time of the day
是个蟹黄堡肉饼
That's a Krabby Patty
又冷又硬
It's cold and hard
可能好多年前就滚到那里去了
This could have rolled there years ago
没事了  小家伙
There, there, little one
你一生的旅途就快结束了
your journey is almost over
怎么回事
What happened?
有人想扔掉一块肉饼
Someone tried to throw away a patty
小气夹夹机已为您立省五分二
Pinch-o-matic has saved you 5.2 cents
可是蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
那可是在烤架底下找到的
I found that under the grill
明天把肉饼放蟹黄堡里让客人吃
And tomorrow a customer will find it under his bun
可是
But
它都过期了  冷冰冰的
it's old and it's cold
而且发满了霉
and so very full of mold
那肉饼没卖出去就不准再做
You're not to make another patty until that one is sold
明白吗
Understand?
第二天
上菜了  章鱼哥
Order up, Squidward
万岁
Hooray
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
能不能来个少一点
can I get one with less
雾气的
fog
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squidward
都是蟹老板要求的
Mr. Krabs's orders
管他的
Whatever
给你  先生
Here you are, sir
一份蟹黄堡
one Krabby Patty
我就不明白了
I don't understand
已经好几周都没客人了
We haven't had a customer in weeks
不知道是不是因为换了餐具垫
I wonder if it's the new placemats
什么
What?
餐具垫
Placemats?
你发什么神经
Have you lost your mind?
都要怪那个过期肉饼
It's that old patty
你还想拿它卖给大家吃
you keep trying to sell to everybody
它早都变质了
It's gone bad
变质了
Gone bad?
一派胡言
That's nonsense
拿过来  海绵宝宝
Bring it here, SpongeBob
干嘛关笼子里
Why is it in a cage?
因为它吼我
Because it growled at me
你俩参加海军肯定没法战斗到底
You two would have never have lasted in the navy
来看看你到底多坏
Let's see how bad you are
不行
No
别动
Stay
真乖
That a girl
没事了
There, there
看吧
See?
放心吃
Good enough to eat
看啊
Look
有救护船
An ambulance
来吃
Now, then
急救
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
怎么了  蟹老板
Yes, Mr. Krabs?
一定要把那个肉饼包好
Make sure you wrap up that patty
手术室
我还没吃完
I'm not finished with it yet
蟹老板  真是虚惊一场啊
Well, Mr. Krabs, you gave us quite a scare
我应该会没事吧  医生
So I'm going to be okay, doc?
要是不相信我说的
Well, if you don't want to take my word for it
就直接看你病历好了
let's just check your chart
来看看啊
Let's see here
不会吧
Oh, no
太可怕了
This is terrible
没事吧  医生
Everything okay, doc?
别碰我
Don't touch me
那可不是好兆头
That's not a good sign
不好了  是飞天魔鬼
Oh, no, it's the Flying Dutchman
尤金蟹  你的死期到了
Eugene Krabs, your time has come
我不是尤金蟹  我是
I'm not Eugene Krabs, I'm, uh
哈罗德
Harold
Harold, uh
小花
Flower
抱歉
Sorry
我一定走错病房了
I must have the wrong room
请问一下  护士
Excuse me, nurse?
怎么了
Yes?
我在找尤金蟹
I'm looking for Eugene Krabs
他就在那边那间病房
He's in that room, right there
不对  那间是哈罗德小花的
No, that's Harold Flower's room
哈罗德小花
Harold Flower?
老螃蟹啊
So, Krabs
你自以为能骗得过飞天魔鬼吗
You thought you could fool the Flying Dutchman?
你想找我干什么
What do you want from me?
我来送你
I'm here to escort you
前往所有海底恶棍的安息之处
to the resting place of all bad undersea folk
戴维琼斯柜子
Davy Jones's locker
Davy Jones's locker?
凭什么要过去
Why do I have to go there?
我又没干坏事
I'm not a bad crab
但是你很小气
But you were cheap
小气就是坏事
and being cheap is a terrible thing
下一站
Next stop
戴维琼斯柜子
Davy Jones's locker
戴维琼斯
到了
Here we are
怎么有股臭味啊
Why does it smell so foul?
戴维琼斯常常健身
Davy Jones works out a lot
这些是他的袜子
These are his socks
进去吧
Get in
求你了  飞天魔鬼先生
Please, Mr. Dutchman
我不想进去啊
I don't want to go in there
我什么都愿意做
I'll do anything
求你再给我一次机会吧
Please, give me another chance
得了吧  老螃蟹
Come on, Krabs
有尊严一点
show a little dignity
妈妈
Mommy
好了好了  别哭了
All right, all right, stop your crying
我这就再给你一次机会
I'll give you another chance
但你必须一直大方
But you must always be generous
不许小气
Never cheap
我以水手的身份向你保证
You have my word as a sailor
停业
蟹老板的鼻毛剪子
Mr. Krabs' nose hair clippers
我应该用得上
I could use these
章鱼哥  不应该随便乱翻
Squidward, you shouldn't be going
蟹老板的东西
through Mr. Krabs' belongings
他绝对不愿意
He won't like it
海绵宝宝  医生的话我早告诉你了
SpongeBob, I told you what the doctor said
蟹老板回不来了
Mr. Krabs isn't coming back
给我安静点
Now, keep quiet
这样才听得见保险柜锁声
so I can hear the tumblers in his safe
小子们
Hey, boys
蟹老板  我就知道
Mr. Krabs, I knew it
你还活着
You're alive
章鱼哥  快看
Squidward, look
是蟹老板
it's Mr. Krabs
是不是棒得跟假的一样
Isn't this too good to be true?
还真是
Well, it was
跟你们说  小子们
You know, boys
大病一场让我思绪万千
being sick made me do a lot of thinking
我这一生都在为钱奔波
My whole life has been about money
省钱  赚钱
Saving money, collecting money
摸钱
touching money
你们应该都懂的
Well, you get the picture
但以后不会了
But no more
你们眼前的是全新向善
You're looking at the new, improved
不再小气的蟹老板
non-cheap Mr. Krabs
盛大重新开业
免费
购买
欢迎光临
Welcome, all, welcome
庆贺好时光
你好啊  小朋友
Hello, little one
手上拿的什么
What you got there?
蟹黄堡
A Krabby Patty
那当然了
Of course you do
知道是什么意思吧
You know what that means, right?
我不会饿肚子了
I don't go hungry?
不对  笨蛋
No, silly
意思就是
It means
免费玩具
free toy
谢谢  蟹老板
Gee, thanks, Mr. Krabs
我还以为你是个超级小气鬼呢
I thought you were a cheap old tightwad
原先确实是  孩子
I was, son, I was
免费玩具大家有份
Free toys for everyone
外加免费续杯
And free refills
活在当下
你好啊  小子
Hello, boy
章鱼哥哪去了
Say, where's Squidward?
他好像是在你办公室休息什么的
He's taking one of those break things in your office
我是说  员工休息室
I mean the "employee lounge"
好
Great
不好意思  我蟹黄堡掉了
Excuse me, but I dropped my Krabby Patty
可以再来一个吗
Could I get another one?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
遵命  老板
Yes, sir
蟹堡王店规明确指出
"Krusty Krab policy clearly states
店规
一旦汉堡送达顾客
"that once the burger has reached the customer
就由其自负
it is his/her responsibility"
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
那店规都作古了
That's the old policy
快回去做个新的出来
Now run back and bring out a fresh one
遵命  老板
Aye, aye, sir
抱歉让你误会了
Sorry about the confusion
要免费玩具不
Free toy?
尤金  好兄弟
Eugene, my man
章鱼哥
Squidward
休息得怎么样了
How's the break coming?
应该再休息几小时就行了
Should be over in a couple of hours
叫海绵宝宝给我送蟹黄堡
Have SpongeBob send back a patty
还有冰茶行不行
and an iced tea, will you?
没问题  章鱼哥
Sure thing, Squidward
放松一点
Take it easy
喜欢就餐期间看的电影吗
Are you enjoying your in-meal movie?
这电影连院线都还没上过呢
This movie hasn't even been in the theaters yet
不遗余力服务我尊贵的客人
No expense spared for my valued customers
看看他们表情多快乐
Look at all those happy faces
大方的感觉真好
It sure does feel good to be generous
你邮件来了  尤金
Here's your mail, Eugene
谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
你休息得挺爽嘛
You look rested
对啊  上班睡觉让我容光焕发
Yeah, these naps at work are doing wonders for me
信用卡账单
Credit card bills
这东西果然还是来了
Well, I knew this was coming
来看看损失了多少
Let's see what the damage is
账单
才一万块
Only $10,000
也没多糟
That's not so bad
从今天的利润减掉就行了
I'll just subtract it from today's profit
而且
And
里面也没钱了
there's no money in here
太美妙了
How delightful
章鱼哥  我有点不放心蟹老板
Squidward, I'm worried about Mr. Krabs
我也是
Me, too
这样还怎么领工资
how are we going to get paid?
蟹老板  你还真能心平气和接受破产
Gee, Mr. Krabs, you sure are taking total bankruptcy well
一场噩梦罢了
It's just a bad dream
我反正马上就要醒了
I'll wake up soon
梦
"Dream"?
没错
Sure
我还在住院
I'm still in the hospital
睡得可香了
sleeping like a baby
你今早就出院了
You checked out of the hospital this morning
这是账单
Here's the bill
你是说
You mean
我没做梦吗
I'm awake?
不准再续杯
No more refills
免费汽水
玩具还回来  吃霸王餐的
Give me back them toys, you freeloaders
演完了  小气鬼
Show's over, cheapskate
我今天真幸运
It's my lucky day
一分钱
A penny
你运气全没了
Your luck just ran out
兄弟  轻一点
Hey, man, ease back
你都快弄断我胳膊了
you're crushing my arm
交出那分钱  不然马上让你断臂
Unhand that penny or the arm comes off
你刚刚的表现小气得不得了
That little display of parsimonious penny pinching
所以我要把你关回戴维琼斯柜子
just earned you a nice little spot
in Davy Jones's locker
一辈子
for eternity
我才不小气  我可大方了
I'm not cheap, I'm generous
你刚就为一分钱差点让别人断臂
You almost tore a man's arm off for a penny
多谢帮倒忙  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
你果然没让我失望
I knew I could count on you
那就这样吧
Well, a deal's a deal
出发
Let's go
先给我等一下
Wait just a burger-flipping second
谁这么大胆  敢跟飞天魔鬼顶嘴
Who dares back-sass the Flying Dutchman?
那就是我
That would be me
海绵顶嘴宝宝
SpongeBob Back-sass Pants
你抓错螃蟹了
I say you got the wrong crab
这位蟹老板是最大方
This Mr. Krabs is the most generous
最宽宏大量  最不吝啬的螃蟹
big-hearted, non-skinflinted crab
全海洋就他一个
in the whole sea
他会就为了几块钱出卖你的灵魂
He'd sell your soul for a couple of bucks
我用我灵魂打赌  他肯定不会
I'd bet my soul he wouldn't
那就来赌吧
You got yourself a bet
好吧  老螃蟹
Okay, Krabs
我会让你留下
I'll let you stay
但你要先帮我打赌
but first help me settle a bet
如果只有两个选择  一个是海绵宝宝
If you had to choose between SpongeBob
另一个是我口袋里的所有钱
and all the money in my pocket
你会怎么选
which would you take?
看情况
That depends
这钱有多少
how much money we talking about?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
六毛二
Sixty-two cents
钱我收了
I'll take the money
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
拿去吧  老螃蟹
Here you go, Krabs
六毛二
Sixty-two cents
下一站  戴维琼斯柜子
Next stop Davy Jones's locker
章鱼哥你看  有钱
Look, Squidward, money
蟹老板  我竟然会这么说
Mr. Krabs, I can't believe I'm saying this
你怎么可以拿海绵宝宝换六毛二
but how could you trade SpongeBob for 62 cents?
你说我本来还能换更多钱吗
You think I could have gotten more?
他为你挺身而出  结果你把他给卖了
He stuck up for you and you sold him out
你应该为自己感到羞耻
You should be ashamed of yourself
我干了什么好事
What have I done?
再给我一次机会吧
I want another chance
我什么教训都没学到
I didn't learn anything
还失去了我最棒的煎炸厨师
I lost my best fry cook
我不要这臭钱了  我要海绵宝宝回来
I don't want this foul money, I want SpongeBob back
给  带回去
Here, take him back
你听见我刚刚说钱的话了吗
You heard what I said about the money?
听你说什么了
Heard what you said?
这家伙吵得我集中不了注意力
I couldn't hear myself thinking with this one around
我才抓了他三十秒
I only had him for 30 seconds
他就一会儿捉水母
and it's jellyfishing this
一会儿美人鱼战士的
and Mermaidman that
不还回去怎么得了
What "not giving him back"?
有他简直是活受罪
He's a fate worse than death
自己带网
Bring your own net
他现在是你的问题了
He's your problem now
先前把你卖了换零钱的事
About trading you for pocket change
不用多说  蟹老板
Say no more, Mr. Krabs
你都是为了蟹堡王着想
You did it for the Krusty Krab
我这情况也会把你卖了
I would have done the same thing
真的吗
You would have?
假的
No
飞天魔鬼家
Dutchman's residence
我先前说到
So, as I was saying
咱俩要多逛逛
you and me got to hang out more
你哪天晚上有空
Well, what nights are good for you
我下面几晚都行
Here are the nights that are good for me
周一二三四五六日
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday
Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday
我得上班
I gotta work
工位在蟹堡王
I work at the Krusty Krab
好朋友是派大星
My best friend is Patrick
他是粉的
He's pink
我出了事故
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
沙山
死亡
我又死了
I got dead again
垃圾游戏
This game stinks
看吧  所以你必须时时刻刻
See, that's why you must always
小心注意高山
pay attention to the mountain
我听着你呢  高山
I'm listening to you, mountain
别吃黄沙  派大星
Don't eat the yellow sand, Patrick
啊对  我都忘了
Oh, yeah, I forgot
珊迪  看我表演暴躁章鱼哥
Hey, Sandy, watch me do the "Grouchy Squidward"
别用我名字称呼你的表演
Stop naming moves after me
大家都是白痴  只有我不是
Everybody's an idiot except for me
本来就这样
Well, it's true
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
小心那棵树
Look out for that tree
放心  一切全在掌控之中
Don't worry, everything's under control
因为我是专家
'cause I'm an expert
真奇怪
That's funny
这山被谁倒过来了
someone turned the mountain upside-down
海绵宝宝  用屁股着陆
SpongeBob, land on your bottom
可以缓冲坠落带来的冲击力
It'll cushion the impact of the fall
这样吗
Like this?
不对  另一个屁股
No, your other bottom
你就不能到别处去犯傻吗
Don't you have to be stupid somewhere else?
要到四点才行
Not until four
一定很疼
That's got to hurt
再来一遍  我刚没看到
Do it again, I wasn't looking
医院
看来你的臀大肌
Well, it looks like your gluteus maximus
急诊
已经痊愈了
has made a full recovery
我什么已经什么了
My what has a what now?
你屁股康复了
Your butt's all better
X光
实在是神奇
It's really quite amazing
我们花了二十小时才成功拼了回去
It took 20 hours to put it all back together
不过缝合钉用完了  只好换了胶水
We actually ran out of staples
and had to use a glue stick
没错  你简直是个
Yep, you're a
幸运幸运幸运幸运幸运幸运儿
lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky, luck-boy
但是从现在起
But from now on
你必须多加小心
I'd like you to be more careful
一旦再次那样受伤
One more injury like that
后果就有可能跟那边那位可怜虫一样
and you could wind up like that poor creature there
戴上铁屁股
In the Iron Butt
天啊  痒死了
Oh, man, it itches
听见医生的话了吧  海绵宝宝
You heard the doctor, SpongeBob
一旦再次那样受伤  就得戴铁屁股
one more injury like that and it's the Iron Butt
我那时太大意了
I've been too careless back there
从现在起  我要无时无刻保护好屁股
From now on I am on round-the-clock butt patrol
离我屁股远点
Step away from the backside
我警告你
I'm warning you
你什么毛病
What's your problem?
好险啊
That was close
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
过来一起打球吧
Why don't you join us?
再来一个球员就够了
We need an extra player
接得好啊  珀西
Nice catch, Percy
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
一定要来试试这个  兄弟
You've got to try this, dude
总算要凑齐人头
We finally got enough people
一起组成七里长的拍屁股大队了
for a seven-mile spanking machine
下一位
Next
队伍是从这排吗
Is this where the line starts?
屁股在外面不安全
My butt is not safe out here
不管哪个部位都不安全
No part of me is safe
好  牛仔骑大马
Yeah, ride 'em, cowboy
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
刚刚太好玩了
That was fun
海绵宝宝  准备好再去滑沙了没
Hey, SpongeBob, you ready to go sand-boarding again?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
朋友们好
Hello, friends
在外面的世界还开心吗
Enjoying the outside world?
你那样坐地板上干什么
What y'all doing
sitting in the middle of the floor like that?
度过余生
Living out the remainder of my life
万事平安
in safety
聪明点的都会跟我一起闭门不出
If you guys were smart, you would join me
那场事故让我醒悟
That accident made me realize
了解到外面的世界分外危险
that it's dangerous out there
而我是一名幸运儿
I was one of the lucky ones
一名幸存者
I'm a survivor
所以我就此决定
And so I've simply decided
我绝对不会再出家门一步
I am never leaving my house again
好一个疯话
That's crazy talk
那又不是疯话
That's not crazy talk
这才是疯话
This is crazy talk
抱歉
Sorry
不对
No
派大星说得才对  珊迪
Patrick's right, Sandy
你都看到我先前的下场了
You saw what happened to me
下次出事  伤的可不只会是屁股
and next time it won't just be my butt
还会是胳肢窝  或者额头
it'll be my armpit or my forehead
或者另一个胳肢窝
Or your other armpit
我本就不该违背自然规律
I was wrong to go against nature
我可是海绵
I'm a sponge
我在胡思乱想什么
What was I thinking?
走路
Walking
我的同类天性就是待着不动
my people are sedentary
你光坐在家里吗
Just sitting in your house?
就不会寂寞吗
Ain't you going to get lonesome?
不会寂寞的
I won't be lonesome
我所有挚友都在呢
I've got all the friends I need here
这位是硬币
This is Penny
还有薯片
And Chip
还有问候一下用过的纸巾
And say hello to Used Napkin
蟹堡王的工作你要怎么办
How are you going to keep your job at the Krusty Krab?
没问题的
No problem
用特别长的锅铲就行了
A really long spatula
吃东西怎么办
What about eating?
我可是海绵
I'm a sponge
滤食就行了
I'll just filter-feed
海绵宝宝  你迟早得出门
SpongeBob, sooner or later
you're going to have to go outside
听好  我都说了
Listen, I told you
我绝对不会再出家门一步
that I'm never leaving my house again
绝对不会吗
Never-ever?
绝对绝对不会
Never-ever-ever
绝对绝对绝对永远不会吗
Never-never-ever-ever for never-ever?
绝对绝对绝对绝对永远永远不会
Never-ever-never-never, ever-ever-never
绝对绝对绝对绝对绝对绝对不会吗
Never-ever-ever- ever-ever-ever-ever-ever?
绝对绝对绝对不会
Never-ever-never-ever
派大星  说够了吧
All right, Patrick, that is enough
薯片  能麻烦你送这两位到门口吗
Chip, would you mind showing these two to the door?
谢了  薯片
Thank you, Chip
看来只能另外再交个好朋友了
I guess I'll have to find a new best friend
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
不要
No
放心  派大星
Don't worry, Patrick
非要让海绵宝宝出门不可
We'll get SpongeBob to come outside
让他知道根本没什么好怕的
and then he'll see there's nothing to be afraid of
出了门马上就打他对吧
And that's when I punch him, right?
快看外面的水母啊
Look at the jellyfish out here
可惜海绵宝宝就要错过这么多乐趣了
Too bad SpongeBob is missing out on all the fun
捉到一只了
I caught one
看那些白痴冒生命危险去捉水母
Look at those fools risking their lives jellyfishing
不过我这新爱好安全多了  对吧薯片
My new hobby is much safer, isn't it, Chip?
捉灰尘
Dust collecting
好像捉到一粒了
I think I caught one
得换点别的办法
We've got to try something else
欢呼三声
Three cheers
庆祝你生日  海绵宝宝
On your birthday, SpongeBob
欢呼三声庆祝你
Three cheers for you
快来吹蜡烛许愿吧
Now, you've got to blow out the candles and make a wish
我不用许愿  硬币
I don't need the wish, Penny
我想要的一切都在这里
Everything I could ever want is right here
不如来唱咱们原创的歌
In fact, let's sing our own song
就唱待在屋里有多快活吧
about the joy of staying indoors
我知道一个地方  保你平安不受伤
I know of a place where you never get harmed
这个神奇地方  有着神奇魅力
A magical place with magical charms
屋里  屋里
Indoors, indoors
屋里
indoors
接着唱  硬币
Take it away, Penny
硬币的歌声简直是天籁
That Penny has the most beautiful voice
真是够了  海绵宝宝
That is it, SquarePants
我们一定要找到特别好玩的事情
We're going to find something that's so dang fun
让你非出门不可
that you'll have to come outside
蹦床
Trampoline
冰淇淋
Ice cream
海底冲浪
Underwater surfing
两个冰淇淋
Two ice creams
摩天轮
Ferris wheel
还是两个冰淇淋
Still two ice creams
跟蛤蜊摔跤
Clam wrestling
给老人家洗澡
Washing an old person
派大星  那个不好玩
Patrick, that's not fun
我觉得好玩
It is for me
全都不行  派大星
Nothing's working, Patrick
该怎么办
What do we do?
不然洗澡吧
I say we take a bath
什么
What
你能不能给我走开
Will you get out of here?
别忘了
Now, remember
等我发信号再跳出来
don't jump out until I give the signal
好
Right
海绵宝宝  算你赢了
All right, SpongeBob, you win
你永远待在家里吧
Stay inside forever
你意志简直跟钢铁一样
Yours is truly the iron will
趁现在  派大星
Now, Pat
有只大猩猩
A gorilla
救救我啊  海绵宝宝
Save me, SpongeBob
我说真的
Okay, guys, really
你们这次的尝试最可悲了
This is your saddest attempt yet
就连薯片都知道那是派大星
Even Chip knows that's Patrick
穿着去年万圣节穿过的扮装服
in the same costume he wore for Halloween last year
不对  真的
No, really
你一定要来救救我
You've got to come save me
珊迪
Hey, Sandy
你朋友谁啊
who's your friend?
可是
But
可是你应该要穿着猩猩服啊
but you're supposed to be in the gorilla suit
我就穿着猩猩服啊
I am in the gorilla suit
我明明干得还行啊
I thought I was doing a pretty good job
既然你是派大星  那他是谁
If you're Patrick, then who's that?
真的是大猩猩
A real gorilla
不要
No
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh
不可能的事
This can't be happening
跟我说的简直一模一样
This is exactly the kind of thing I was talking about
反正是他们自找的
Well, they were asking for it
我都警告过他们外面多危险了
It's not like I didn't warn them
about the dangers of outside
对啊  薯片
Yes, Chip
我知道他俩是我全世界最亲近的朋友
I know they're my two dearest friends in the whole world
但我都说过了  不管怎样我都不出门
but I told them I wasn't going outside no matter what
不人身攻击也行的
We can do without the name-calling
多谢你了  用过的纸巾
thank you very much, Used Napkin
对啊  薯片
I know, Chip
如果我被大猩猩装进袋子里
if it was me out there bagged by an ape
派大星跟珊迪肯定会不惜代价救我的
Patrick and Sandy would risk anything to save me
我也一定要不惜代价救他们
And I've got to do the same for them
要是我回不来  薯片
If I don't come back, Chip
照顾小蜗
take good care of Gary
好吧
Well
我要走了
here I go
离开家里安全的舒适圈
from the safety of my home
走向外面的世界
to the outside world
我要踏出第一步了
I'm taking my first step
目前平安无事
So far so good
我应该能行的
I think I can do this
不要
No
我的海神王啊
Oh, dear Neptune
快弄下去
Get off of me
薯片  救命
Chip, help me
救命
help me
我还活着
I'm still alive
成功了
I did it
我成功出门了
I made it outside
什么东西都没法阻止我了
Nothing can stop me now
现在回屋里还来得及吗
Is it too late to go back inside yet?
来不及了
It's too late
派大星
Patrick?
珊迪
Sandy?
怎么了  海绵宝宝
Yeah, SpongeBob?
对不起  都是我害的
I'm sorry I caused all this
我再也不怕出门了
I'm not scared of going outside anymore
但我怕大猩猩了
But I'm terrified of gorillas now
没事的  海绵宝宝
That's okay, SpongeBob
我们也怕
us, too
不过知道我还不理解什么事吗
You know what I don't understand, though?
什么
What?
大猩猩来海底干嘛来着
What's a gorilla doing underwater in the first place?
那个
Well
这么问还真有点怪
it's funny you should
就是那个
I mean, you see, the
乔治  我们穿帮了
George, they're onto us
快逃吧
Let's get out of here
本集完